Guide to the Doris Duke American Indian oral history project audio recordings 1949-1972
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Chief Jack House (Mountain Ute), 1967 September 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 139)
  Beaver Creek Massacre, land controversy, land leases at Mesa Verde.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Gregory C. Thompson in Durango, Colorado. Interpreted by Warren Pyle.
- John Pendelton, Milt Daily, Joseph McGregor, Amelia Topham, Nellie Clark (Non-Natives associated with Paiutes), 1968 January; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 140)
  Arts and crafts, legends, food, burial custom, Parowan gap, heiroglyphics, travel, marriage, wars, Caucasian-Native American relations, religion, language.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 4 minutes.
- Ralph Cloud (Southern Ute), 1967 September 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 141)
  Migrations, language, differences between various reservations, arts and crafts, humor, education, hunting, story telling, historical tales, legends.
- Mildred Morrison (Non-Native Associated with Paiutes), Parowan Children, 1968 February; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 142)
  Legends, Caucasian-Native American relations, marriage, Mormon-Native American relations, family relationships.
- Warren Pyle (Non-Native Associated with Mountain Utes), 1967 September 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 143)
  First settlers in Dolores Valley, trade, chiefs, reservation conditions, land claims, education, religion, Native American-Caucasian relations, present condition of the Ute tribe.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Gregory C. Thompson in Cortez, Colorado.
- Nellie Coston (Non-Native Associated with Southern Utes), 1967 September 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 144)
  History and ancestry, Native American-Caucasian relations, mines, Fort Lewis, Massacres, polygamy.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 49 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Gregory C. Thompson in Mancos, Colorado.
- Elbert Floyd (Non-Native Associated with Southern Utes), 1967 September 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 145)
  Agents, agriculture, differences in Utes, today and yesterday, education, Anglo relations, land claims, Whitemesa Utes, Allen Canyon Utes, poverty.
- Orville C. Day (Non-Native Associated with Utes), 1967 September 23; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 146)
  Personal background, uses for pine trees, Native American crops destroyed by the White Man, land disputes, trek to winter quarters from California, farming in the early days of Utah, boy's experience with squaw, settling of Manti, custom of abandoning old women, death of a small Native American boy, Chief Walker, Pioneer medical care, Chief Walker courting a white girl, Pioneer woman outsmarting renegades, grasshoppers, Caucasian-Native American misunderstandings, white woman brands a Buck.
  A-Cass Tape, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 51 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by D. Corydon Hammond in American Fork, Utah.
- Eugene Naranjo (Pueblo), 1967 September 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 147)
  Topics discussed include: Childhood, harvesting crops, current day life, controversial anthropological studies in Santa Clara, and interactions with the Mormon Church.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 31 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Richard Potter in Santa Clara Pueblo, New Mexico.
- Henry Old Coyote (Crow), 1967 October 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 148)
  Native American districts, education, history of the Crow, the retreat of Chief Joseph, Medicine Men, war societies, traditions, influence of the white men, sources of Native American history.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 56 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil in the Crow Agency, Montana.
- Tom Polacca, 1967 September 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 149)
  How to collect Hopi history, Hopi-Anglo relations.
  Interviewed and recorded by Charles Peterson in Moencopi, Arizona.
- Ester Bilegody (Hopi), 1967 September 13; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 150)
  Mrs. Bilegody's Father, pottery, Mrs. Bilegody's history, occupations, tribal government, childhood, family relations.
  Second half of CD (half of track five- throught the end) is an interview between Charles Peterson and Mr. William Numkina.
- Lillian Anderson (Non-Native American Associated with the Hualapai), 1967 September 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 151)
  Arrival at Valentine Mission, relations with the Native Americans, Religion and education, deaths by teberculosis, measles epidemic, pow wows for dying people, relations with native American Elders, burial customs, first caskets for the Native Americans, marriage customs, food preferences, living off the land, living conditions, divorce, children, Apache and Mojave influences on the Hualapai, the Gohst Dance, Government Movement of Native Americans, ambush of a wagon train, rumor of a medicine man poisening patients, soldier-Native American relations, Native American resentment regarding the treatment of ancestors, clothing, basskets, Chapels.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 38 minutes.
  Interviewed and Recorded by Mildred D. Maher in Valentine, Arizona.
- Lillian Anderson (Non-Native American Associated with the Hualapai), 1967 September 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 152)
- Wilfred Babcock (Non-Native American Associated with the Hualapai), 1967; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 153)
  Orgin of Hualapai name, Fort Mojave, Caucasian-Native American relations, Hualapai War, mining, Mojave-Hualapia differences and relations, the Gohst Dane od 1889, Hualapai reaction to jail, Religion, dance, burial ceremonies, recreation, the coming of the Spanish, life in the early Kingman, alcohol, family relations, life at early Fort Hall, shopping, the Navajo additude towards Caucasians.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 47 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Bob Carr in Kingman, Arizona.
- Mr.Nephi and Mrs.Mildred Morrison (Non-Native Associated with Paiutes), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 154)
  Caucasian-Native America Relations, food, Christmas, religion.
  Interviewed and recorded by Alva Matheson in Cedar City, Utah.
- Nunuche and Old Enote (Zuni), 1968 September 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 155)
  Food, child-parent relations, hunting, recreation, transvestites, witches, traders, misssionaries.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 16 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by D. Corydon Hammond and Gloria Hammondin Zuni, New Mexico.
- Joe Roberts (Elko Colony), 1968 Summer; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 156)
  Language, hippies, peyote, words, medicine, ancestry, pine nuts, recreation, raillraod, marriage, employment, Caucasian-Native American relations, farming, hunting, World War II, water, place names, Fandango, travel, military service, shelters, clothes, Medicine Men, names, songs, hair, time concept, factionalism, Civil Rights, Bureau of Native American Affairs, politics, Vietnam, religion, story telling, plant names, cosmetics, population, migratory patterns, horses, transportation, acculturation, generation gap, economics, polygamy, puberty, tribal politics, environment, epidemics, history, mythology legends, Shoshoni-Paiute relations, arts and crafts.
  Available compact disc copy (4 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 41 minutes.
  Ethnographic notes gathered by Joe Roberts in Elko, Nevada.
- Lorenzo Chavez (Zuni), 1968 September 13; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 157)
  Religion, migration, life at Towa'Yallone, trade, famines, Zuni-Navajo-Apache relations, scalp dance.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 158-167)
- Willie ( Guillermo) Labato (Apache), 1968 September 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 168)
  Ancestry, cattle, Wirt, Emmett, arts and crafts, hunting.
  Interviewed and recorded by Dr. Robert Delaney in Durango, Colorado.
- Recording unavailable (Reel 169)
- Roe Palmer (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), Oscar Hulet, Hazel Trougher, 1968 January 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 170)
  Names, Caucasian-Native American relations, alcohol, standard of living, reservations, education.
  2 reel-to-reel audiotapes, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 4 minutes.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 171-190)
- Fred Conetah (Ute), 1969; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 191)
  Travel, National Archives, Inauguration.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 192-194)
- Muse Harris (Northern Ute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 195)
  Life near the river, blue cornmeal, Native American visitors and friends, squaw giving birth, Native American beggars and thieves, migratory Native Americans, Utes considered friendly, medicine, Ute-Paiute-Shoshoni-Sioux War, Buffalo hunt, trading post, Nupigut, burial customs, education.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 196-203)
- Social Science-"The Angry Indians", 1961 June 20; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 204)
  "Angry Indian Chicago Conference"
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 24 minutes.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 205-254)
- Lynn Lyman (Non-Native Associated with Paiutes), 1967 December 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 255)
  Jim Mike, Rainbow Bridge, Poke and Posey War.
  Interviewed and recorded by Charles Peterson in Blanding, Utah.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 256-266)
- Jasper Pike (Ute), 1969 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 267)
  Caucasian-Native American relations, education, Chiefs, African American Soldiers, rations, Matt Warner, Sun Dance, Bear Dance, Fort Robidoux, Reed Enterprize, merchants, entertainment, peyote, Tabby White, The Strip.
  Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver in Whiterocks, Utah.
- Jasper Pike (Ute), 1969 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 268)
  Chief Tabby, Fort Duchesne, mining, Grandma Daniels.
- Harry Richards, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 269)
  Symbols and mythology.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 6 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded in Ignacio Colorado.
- George Walkup (Ute), 1969 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 270)
  Chief Atchee, alcohol, Meeker Massacre.
- Henry Harris Jr. (Ute), 1969 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 271)
  Reed Enterprise, religion, Sun Dance, migration, The Strip, Butch Cassidy, Fort Duchesne, Chinese Merchants.
  Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver in Vernal, Utah.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 272-280)
- Albert Daniels (Born Navajo, Adopted by Utes), 1969 August 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 281)
  Food, superintendents, Rose Daniels, Sun Dance, education, Fort Duchesne, Native American-Caucasian relations, Chiefs, Chinese merchants.
- Muse Harris (Uintah Band), 1969; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 282)
  Family history, Whiterocks Utah.
  Reel-to-Reel-A-Tape, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 28 minutes.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 283-287)
- Father Kraft Niles (Non-Native Associated with Zuni), 1968 September 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 288)
  Missions, religion, education, mission restoration
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time minutes.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 289-296)
- Sarah Van Hackford (Northern Ute), 1968 January 31; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 297)
  Personal history and ancestry, religion, allotments, migration, Inter-Band relations, Intermarriage, Segregation, difference of Native American Culture and White Culture, farming, land, law, discrimination in the Church, education, termination, horses, Wheeler and Howard Acts.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil in Lapoint, Utah.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 298-321)
- William Carmack Speech, 1968 February 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 322)
  William Carmack Speech, next tape contains Panel Discussion regarding Alienation of the American Indians.
- Panel Discussion: Alienation of the American Indian, 1968 February 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 323)
  Panel Discussion regarding Alienation of the American Indians.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 58 minutes.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 324-328)
- Jimmie Pete, Carl Jake (Paiute), 1968 January 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 329)
  Carl Jake:
  Bear Dance, Recreation.
  Jimmie Pete:
  Recreation, hunting, Chiefs, Mountain Meadow Massacre, old Native American race track, Parowan, Native words, hieroglyphics, buried Hopi Civilization, different tribes.
- Jimmie Pete (Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 330)
  Jimmie Pete: Tracks 1-5
  The origin of the Bear Dance, Funeral song, peyote, old Native American racetrack in western Cedar, pine nuts,
  Tracks 5-13
  Excerts from a tape Ella Matheson made for the state historical society.
- Jimmie Pete; Annie, Zella, Alva, Rhoda Matheson; Tom Lawrence (Paiute, Non-Natives Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 330-I)
  Jimmie Pete: Tracks 1-3
  Native American-Pioneer relations, Parowan, domestic utensils, trade, Paiute-Shoshoni relations, clothing, shelters, bath houses, burial customs.
  Annie Matheson: Tracks 3-4
  Native American story.
  Alva Matheson: Tracks 4-6
  "A White Man's vision", Native American graves, incident with a bear.
  Tom Lawrence: Tracks 6-8
  Life in and around early Southern Utah Territory.
  Rhoda Matheson Wood: Tracks 8-11
  Treatment of twins.
- Carl Jake (Paiute), Mr. Van Buren, 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 331)
  Shelters and food, burial customs, relocation, basket weaving, Indian Peak, hieroglyphics, Paiute-Shoshoni trade, seed gathering, old characters, Mountain Meadow Massacre, Paiute-Navajo relations.
  Disc 1
  Carl Jake: Tracks 1-4
  Mr. F C Van Buren: Track 5-7
  Carl Jake: Tracks 7-13
  Disc 2
  mix of interviews
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 9 minutes.
- unkown, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 331-II)
  Unidentified interviewee, working with a translator during interview.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 4 minutes.
- Calvin Connell, Milt Daily; F.C. Van Buren, Zella Matheson (Non-Natives Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 332)
  F.C. Van Buren: Track 1-3
  Native American graves, leather treatment, symbolism common to Native Americans, Mormons and Masons, loss of arts and crafts, religion, decline of culture and morals, anecdotes.
  Zella Matheson: Track 1-2
  Caucasian-Native American similarities in the story of.
  Calvin Connel: Tracks 3-6
  Caucasian-Native American relations, anecdotes, bear traps.
  Milt Daily: Tracks 6-13
  Anecdotes.
- Lillian Daily, Milt Daily (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 333)
  Trading and selling children, harvesting wheat, food.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 8 minutes.
- Alva Matheson, Zella Matheson (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 334)
  Native American justice, Itinerant workers, education, living conditions, loss of culture, freights and stagecoach hold-ups, work abilities, buying and trading children, intermarriage, arts and crafts, male-female relations, Native American Legends:,,,.
  Interviewed and recorded by Inez Cooper in Cedar City, Utah.
- Alva Matheson, Zella Matheson (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 335)
  Loss of culture, origin of the Bear Dance, family life, funeral customs, living conditions before the White Man, Anglo influence, attitudes toward Caucasians, relocation, Black Hawk War, settling of Panguitch.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 39 minutes.
- Alva Matheson, Zella Matheson (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 336)
  Childhood Native American friends, settlement habits, Caucasian-Native american relations, important Chiefs, early settlers of Southern Utah, different tribes in Southern Utah, Mountain Meadow Massecre, Federal Policy, early L.D.S. Native American relations, treatment of infants, courting customs, trading children and Squaws, anecdotes, Chief Kanosh, rock paintings, hieroglyphics and thier meanings, Religion, orgin of the Navajo Legend, Wars, renegades, Caucasian-Native American relations, Spanish Gold mining, uprisings, arts and crafts, shelters.
- Alva Matheson, Zella Matheson (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 337)
- Alva Matheson, Zella Matheson (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 338)
- Alva Matheson, Zella Matheson (Non-Native Associated with Paiute), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 339)
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 340-349)
- Haddie Ariwhite (Shoshoni), 1968 February 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 350)
  How Tendoy became Chief, the Bear Children and the Deer Children Legends, The Rabbit and the Sun Legend.
  Appears on page 53 of an accompanying manuscript.
  2 reel-to-reel audiotapes, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 23 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Lorin Gaarder in Idaho.
- Zuni Navo (Bannock), 1968 February 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 351)
  Encounter between Lemhi-Bannock and a band of Blackfeet, story of one young man who fought in a Shoshoni battle with strangers, a battle involvong four groups of Native Americans, how a Nimi Camp was warned of a Blackfeet raiding party and how they escaped, how a shoshoni woman escaped from her Blackfeet captor, the Deer Children and the Bear Children, and the Rabit tale.
  Stories appear on pages 92, 83 and 98 of accompanying manuscript.
  2 reel-to-reel audiotapes, compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 13 minutes.
  Interviewed by Lorin Gaarder in Idaho.
- Henry Woonsook (Shoshoni, Bannock), 1968 February 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 352)
  Henry Woonsook's Grandmother's tale of The Bear River Battle.
  Interviewed and recorded by Lorin Gaarder in Fort Hall, Idaho.
- Raymond George (Shoshoni), 1967 February 23; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 353)
  Raymond George's Grandfather's tale about the Bannock War.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 354-358)
- Alex Erickson, 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 359)
  Early Chloride, recreation, medicine.
- Helen Livingston Shawl (Non-Native Associated with Hualapai), 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 360)
  Interviewed and recorded by Mojave County Museum in Chloride, Arizona.
- Mr & Mrs George Walkup (Ute), 1969 August; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 361)
  Living on the reservation for sixty-one years.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 13 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Norma Denver.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 362-365)
- Cecelia P. Lambeth (Apache), 1968 March 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 366)
  Background, education, plants, marriage, horses, ancestry, legends, arts and crafts, clothes, recreation, Native American-Caucasian relations, reservation life, children, home life, religion, language.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 59 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Mr. and Mrs. Alva Matheson in Cedar City, Utah.
- Willemina B. Vanderwagon (Zuni), 1968 September 13; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 367)
  Teaching at the mission school at Zuni. School activities. Changes in the community over the years. Impact of television on Zuni children.
- Ernie Vanderwagon (Zuni), 1968 September 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 368)
  Life in Zuni during the depression, growing and storing food. Zuni blessings, stick race. Changes in the villiage, pictures of Zunis, alcohol.
- Lorenzo Chavez (Zuni), 1968 September 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 369)
  Spanish period in Zuni.
- Boots Siruch, Edeeth Siruch, Katheleen Chegup, 1968; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 370)
  Native American songs.
  Reel-to-reel audiotapes, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 29 min
  Recorded by Norma Denver from the Western History Center.
- Linda Pawwannie (Ute), 1968 September 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 371)
  Uncompahgre Band: First Ute group to tour Europe on an educational trip.
- Marietta Reed (Ute), 1968 September 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 372)
  Uncompahgre Band: Termination.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 22 minutes.
- Tom Premo, Erldean Harny (Shoshoni), 1967 June 19; 1967 August 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 373)
  Duck Valley Reservation, Captain Buck, the Pine Nut story, Coyote and Power.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 6 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Hee Kyung Kim.
- Charles Burke, 1968 Septmerb 13; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 374)
  'The Last of the Indian Wars', Indian rights association, violence, personal stories of working as a reporter, christian missions.
  Recorded in Durango Colorado.
  Interviewed by FLoyd O'Niel and Gregory Thompson.
- J. Blackhat (Shoshoni), John Harny, Lucy Jones, Frank Keefe, 1967 June 24; 1967 June 29; 1967 July 24; 1967 August 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 375)
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 48 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Hee Kyung Kim in Owyhee, Nevada. Translated by Lucy Jones.
- Sadie Benally (Navajo), 1968 July 02; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 376)
  Translation of Interview w/ Sadie Benally informant, Clyde Benally interpreter.
  Arranged marriage, marriage ceremony, raising children, schooling, voting, problems facing Navajo people.
  2 reel-to-reel audiotapes, compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 20 minutes. I_01 translation, II_01_original interview.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway. Translated by Benjamin Lee.
- Sadie Benally (Navajo), 1968 June 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 377)
  Translation of Interview with Sadie Benally
  The Mission, John Johnson, Dan Hayes, Father Leibler, farm and irrigation project.
  2 reel-to-reel audiotapes, compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 22 minutes. I_01 Translated interview, II_01 Original interview.
- Sadie Benally (Navajo), 1968 July 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 378)
  Working on the mission farm, storing food, having their sheep, goats, horses and donkeys herded away from them. I_01 Translated interview, II_01 Original interview between Sadie Benally and Gary Shumway.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 3 minutes.
- Jim Garnenez, 1968 July 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 379)
  Range control, land ownership, grazing, local politics, the present and future for Navajo people, life on the reservation.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway in Shiprock, NM.
- Jim Garnenez, 1968 July 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 380)
  Negative response to individuals working towards progress, federal government's effect on the Navajo people, youth and education, housing, industry in the area.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 1 minute.
- Alfrieda Garnenez, 1968 July 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 381)
  Family background, leaving the reservation, education, moving to Shiprock, public health services, doctors and hospitals in Shiprock, personal stories of grandparents, childhood, church, rug weaving,
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 12 minutes.
- Natoni Garnenez, 1968 July 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 382)
  Childhood experiences, schooling, the flu, work experiences, opening a gas station, farming, wife's experiences, talking to the grandchildren about the Navajo language.
- Henry Garnenez, 1968 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 383)
  Migrant work on reservations, employee/employer relations.
  Interview is on side 1 tracks 1-3 tracks 4-7 contain unidentified native song/dance from some type of live performance or competition. Side 2 is a continuation of the singing/dancing that concluded side 1.
  Interviewed and recorded by Gary Shumway.
- Tom Stash, 1968 July 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 384)